

## BENJAMIN NYAORO

#### USER EXPERIENCE RESEARCHER

## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a User Experience (UX) researcher with Web Development skills and a solid background in finance and accounting based in Frankfurt am Main area, Germany. I stand at the cross section of finance and technology leveraging my knowledge, skills, and experience in both fields to create products that address user pain points.

## **CONTACT**



**EMAIL** 



+49 1590 4867 314



**PORTFOLIO** 

nyaorobenjamin.com



**ADDRESS** Frankfurt, Main

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Web 101, how the web works Terminal basic commands Git basic commands HTML / CSS foundations JavaScript foundations Tech workflows and tools in a Startup Ruby on Rails Adobe XD, Figma, InVision

#### **UX SKILLS**

User Research Information Architecture Wireframing Prototyping **Usability Testing** Journey Maps

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

English (Native) Swahili (Native) German (Beginner)

## **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

#### **Full Stack Web Development, Germany**

Le Wagon - Berlin, Germany

Ruby on Rails Full Stack web development course that trains on building web applications from scratch.

#### **Certified User Experience Designer, Germany**

DEC 2020 - MAR 2021

JAN 2022 - JUN 2022

CareerFoundry - Online Project-Based Design

Project-based mentor-guided UX Design course where I designed user cantered that address user pain points.

#### **Certified SME Finance Expert, Germany**

OCT 2019 - SEP 2020

Frankfurt School of Finance & Management, Germany

Training on SME Finance principles and designing learning modules of training entrepreneurs on these principles.

#### Master in SME Promotion & Training, Germany

OCT 2016 - SEP 2018

Universität Leipzig, Germany

Thesis Topic: Analysing the Decision-Making approach of SMEs entrepreneurs while internationalizing their firms.

**Bachelor of Business Management** (Finance and Banking)

OCT 2011 - DEC 2014

Moi University, Kenya

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **User Experience Researcher**

SEP 2021 - Current

**EURO PAYMENT GROUP** 

Industry: Fintech, ewallet, PSP

- Engaging stakeholders in the business unit to understand business needs & match it against user needs and turn the feedback into actionable UX concepts.
- Talking to users and stakeholders and translating their needs into UX concepts to pass to developers for implementation.
- Creating user stories and designing the resulting user flows to be implemented and evaluating the flows post implementation.
- Led in-depth qualitative research with users, as well as key stakeholders; and reporting out findings to the development team and product owner to improve the existing the designs.

## **User Experience Design Consultant**

AUG 2020 - AUG 2021

INTERNATIONAL RESCUE COMMITTEE (IRC)

Industry: Software, Non-Profit, Non-Government Services

- Based on user feedback, designing initial journey maps, navigation design, sitemaps, information architecture, wireframes, storyboards, mockups and prototypes to improve the current designs.
- Analysing user feedback and translating them into UX concepts to develop recommendations of improving the existing designs.
- Leading in-depth qualitative interviews with users, as well as key stakeholders; and advising the development team and product owner based on findings to improve the existing the designs.
- Leading the testing and review of learning content before they are launched to ensure they meet quality standards.
- Advising the learning team on how to optimize learner journeys on the learning management system (LMS)

## **Projects Manager**

MAY 2018 - JUL 2020

AWAMO GmbH, Frankfurt

Industry: Software, Fintech, Banking

- Guiding staff to identify the root causes of difficulties they encounter in using the product and help them in developing solutions to address these difficulties.
- Designed customer and employee onboarding to enable convenient learning of the product by both the employee and the customers in 8 branches.
- Conducted and coordinated, product, market, operational and related research to support strategic and business planning within various departments and customer learning.
- Designed and implemented User Acceptance Testing (UAT) training guidelines and oversaw its implementation in testing the product before release to the market.
- Coordinated with development team to align the product with customer requirements and feedback across 6 branches in two countries.

## **Audit and Training Manager**

JAN 2015 - APR 2018

DANIEL AND DANIELS BC, Nairobi

Industry: Business Consulting, Accounting, Auditing

- Recruited and onboarded new employees and retrained the existing ones on new trends in auditing and accounting.
- Designed and implemented audit and training programmes for employees and guided their implementation in the day-to-day audit process.
- Assessed employees' skills, performance, and productivity to identify areas of improvement.
  - Evaluated organizational performance to ensure that training is meeting business needs and improving employee